P it's Glam ham and I have
some
mindblowing dot connecting about
hurricane Helen I'm going to start here
this lady sent this picture from South
Africa you all know I covered the blob
anomaly and South Africa's crazy
weather these blue jelly balls were
raining on this lady's parents she asked
me to look into this here's how this
went and trust me it links back to to
this and it's
mindblowing I start to look into the
jelly balls knowing it's not a craft
project riging from the sky I move on I
find that this is not the first time
that blue jelly balls have been raining
from the sky this was 2012 we'll get
back to that I came across this blue
jelly balls look kind of similar and
this is talking about how we could be
drinking from water bottles made of
these like gummy balls sounds ch in
let's move on thank goodness scientists
looked into this and found out it was
not Marine eggs these jelly blue balls
raining from the sky were made of sodium
polyacrylate so I find out that
polyacrylate has an impact on
temperature and it can be used for
cooling and reflecting it is not
biodegradable and doesn't decompose
quickly in nature which is a little
concerning if it's raining from the sky
so I go back to looking for anything
that looked like a jelly blue ball that
might rain from the sky and I found this
this is droplet mixing with a Pio
electric transducer pzo El electric
transducers are a type of
electroacoustic sound transducer that
converts the electrical charges produced
by some forms of solid material into
energy it is energy
related remember that so I ask AI what
does this have to do with my blue rainy
jelly balls cloud seeding while Paso
Electric devices are not directly used
for cloud seeding they can contribute to
the technology by helping control or
monitor dispersal of the seeding
materials like silver iodide ultrasonic
devices again we have a sound element
here they may use pzo electric
transducers to create sound waves that
influence cloud formation and
precipitation would you look at those
jelly blue balls things you never
thought you'd say there's a sciency
description here of how they're
intertwined but importantly these
hydrophilic polymers can absorb large
amounts of water and you're thinking
probably right now what's this got to do
with hurricane
Helen trust me so we're energy energy
harvesting now in my video last night I
included lithium mining I tread
carefully there cuz I had a video band
now here's the important thing okay the
combination of pzo electric transducers
with blue polyacrylate hydrogels creates
innovative solutions for sensing and
energy harvesting applications again
with the energy harvesting trust me this
gets better here's where a big lightning
bulb went off so this kind of magical
property of converting energy from One
Source Force into something else that's
usable occurs in certain
materials like quartz hold that thought
again we all know there's loads of
lithium out there well did you know
there's a ton of quartz like 530 billion
dollars worth of quartz you may be aware
that the growing use of AI is going to
require a staggering amount of power
while it turns out that quartz while not
powering AI directly has properties that
enable the hardware that powers AI to
function effectively okay we're going to
go back to sound now another message
from South Africa about hearing a
strange humming and sound pulsing well
guess what else has been heard in some
of these freaky
storms carea what is that
noise
what well we know it's sound so from the
comments I quickly gathered that this
sounds like an instrument called a chaar
here's what that sounds like definitely
very similar wrapping this journey that
we've just been on thanks to the Jelly
blue balls some
experimental weather modification
techniques involve ultrasonic devices
which may use pzo El electric
transducers to create sound waves that
can influence cloud
formation and precipitation is this
logic presence of quartz a DOT we need
to connect is the lithium a DOT we need
to connect the sound are the jelly blue
balls
involved this concludes this deep dive
for now anyone interested in emergency
communications see my playlist hurricane
coms for how to get started and how to
use radio in an emergency and hey while
you're at it get your ham radio license
I'll see you in the comments take care
[Music]